Guide to the Tamiment Library Web Archive (Labor and the Left): Education and Student Movements TAM 600
Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives
Tamiment Library Web Archive (Labor and the Left): Education and Student Movements
2009-
TAM 600
Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives
0.1 linear feet (1+ websites: i.e., a collection of websites that grows on an ongoing basis)
The Tamiment Library Web Archive (Labor and the Left): Feminism & Women's Movements, was created with the Web Archiving Service from the California Digital Library, which was made possible with support from the National Digital Information and Infrastructure Preservation Program (Library of Congress) and the University of California, as part of a project to preserve born-digital political communication. The Tamiment Library creates topically based archives of websites documenting labor and left activity, principally that based in the United States, with a particular focus on New York City. The collection contains periodically archived web sites representing progressive student movements and political activity, and and efforts of others, as well as students, to maintain and improve the quality of, and access to, education, and to advocate for progressive educational methods and content. NOTE: if a link for an individual site does not work, click on the TITLE of the collection (in the "Description" section at the beginning of the finding aid) to access this web archive, then go to the site list and select the web site(s) you wish to view.
Tamiment Library.
Historical/Biographical Note
The Tamiment Library Web Archive (Labor and the Left): Anarchism, was created with the Web Archiving Service from the California Digital Library. This service employs open source web archiving utilities developed by Internet Archive with the support of the The International Internet Preservation Consortium. The Web Archiving Service was made possible with support from the National Digital Information and Infrastructure Preservation Program and the University of California, as part of a project to preserve born-digital political communication. The role of the Tamiment Library during this project and thereafter was/is to create topically based archives of websites documenting contemporary and ongoing labor and left activity, principally that based in the United States.
Related Archival Material
A list of related Tamiment Library web archives, whose ns2:titles all begin with the prefix "Tamiment Library Web Archive (Labor and the Left), can be found at the website Web Archives from New York University Libraries
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Scope and Content Note
The collection contains periodically archived web sites representing progressive student movements and political activity, and and efforts of others, as well as students, to maintain and improve the quality of, and access to, education, and to advocate for progressive educational methods and content. There is a particular emphsis on New York City based activity. NOTE: if a link for an individual site does not work, click on the TITLE of the collection (in the "Description" section at the beginning of the finding aid) to access this web archive, then go to the site list and select the web site(s) you wish to view.
- Education and Student Movements
  - AFT ACTS, 5/1/2011-
  - Against Child Trafficking at NYU, 12/15/2009-
  - Amnesty International @NYU, 12/15/2009-
  - Defend Public Education, 2/25/2010-
  - Education Notes Online, 5/10/2010-
  - Grassroots Education Movement, 2/25/2010-
  - Student Peace Action Network, 2/25/2010-
  - Students for a Democratic Society, 2/26/2010-
  - Students for a New American Politics, 2/15/2010-
  - Teachers for a Just Contract, 5/3/2011-
  - Without Walls, 5/5/2011-